MOLLY FITZHARRIS

CONTACT

■molly.fitzharris@gmail.com

in/in/molly-fitzharris

mfitzharris

SUMMARY

As a web developer I am excited by the challenge to make other people's lives better through the tools and processes they use on the web.

PROJECTS

CuriousCorpus

Nov 2016

My capstone project at DBC, CuriousCorpus is a method of predicting an inputted passage of text's period of origin with up to 81% accuracy. For example when analyzing the text of Emily Brontë's Wuthering Heights our algorithm correctly predicts 1800 as the century in which is was written.

The project was written in Python leveraging the SciKit-learn library. Through the training of our models (multinomial naïve bayes, random forest, and support vector machine) with <u>Project Gutenberg's</u> 53,000 free public-domain ebooks we were able to move improve initial 38% accuracy to a high of 81%. My role included researching corporas with which to train our algorithm, the setup and seeding of the database, and development of the naïve bayes classifier.

Our completed project can be viewed at sithub.com/npentella/CuriousCorpus, and its development stages at github.com/lauframo/textorical.

EDUCATION

The School of the Art Institute of Chicago (SAIC)

BFA Art History, Theory, and Criticism 2014 Thesis: Intimate Histories in Nineteenth Century Quilts

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING: Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, Python, Flask, Javascript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Ajax, Angular, SQL, PostgreSQL, Active Record, SQLAlchemy, Git, Agile, TDD, OOD OTHER: Photoshop, Adobe Acrobat, Sketchup, MailChimp, Basecamp, Microfiche, Ouickbooks

EXPERIENCE

Dev Bootcamp (DBC) Student Web Developer Jul 2016 to Nov 2016 Chicago, IL

- During this intensive program I learned the fundamentals of web development via programming in Ruby, Sinatra, Ruby on Rails, and JavaScript (Ajax & jQuery)
- I was also able to learn and practice test driven development (utilizing RSpec & Jasmine), Agile development, pair programming, and the management of team dynamics.
- I completed many projects during DBC. Some of my favorites included building a 2048 clone
 (focusing on integrating a complex JavaScript model with HTML), and a board-game website
 (written in Ruby, I personally focused on the interactions between users and developing a
 friendship model).
- My time at DBC culminated with a team project (CuriousCorpus) which I have described in detail to the left.

LaSalle Network / Tribune Content Solutions Contract Account Manager Mar 2016 to Apr 2016 Chicago, IL

- Oversaw 100+ <u>Tribune Content Solution</u> accounts, ensuring client satisfaction during a period of department transition
- Utilized Basecamp and salesforce to respond to all account requests, directing inquiries as needed to SEO, PPC, and webdev specialists.

Rena Sternberg Fine Art Consulting Art Consulting Assistant

Sep 2015 to Mar 2016 Glencoe, IL

- Organized 20+ tours of galleries, private collections, and museums for clients featuring exclusive artist and curator talks
- Used Quickbooks to perform business's bookkeeping and implemented new process for maintaining records, eliminating redundancies and freeing time to focus on assisting clients and planning tours

Blue Rock Sales & Marketing Marketing Assistant May 2014 to Mar 2016 Barrington, IL

- Coordinated nationwide sales incentive program across multiple companies, ensuring accurate data and its use for increasing brand awareness, leading to a 15% increase in sales
- Created a client database with Access and Excel in order to drive more efficient, targeted marketing

The Art Institute of Chicago Archives Intern

Jun 2012 to Nov 2012 Chicago, IL

- Organized the special collection of Peter Pollack/ Vincent Van Gogh photographs in preparation for the 2013 / 2016 exhibitions What Vincent Saw / Van Gogh: In Search Of
- Ran the digitization project to create an <u>online database</u> of rare early 20th century museum
- Assisted in client based research, utilizing the archives databases